

# MANNY AVILA TRADITIONAL/GRAPHIC ARTIST

CREATIVE SOLUTIONS FOR CREATIVE PROBLEMS

artofavila.com • manny@artofavila.com • 702.807.5413

# **ARTIST STATEMENT**

Ideal creative, with experience creating stunning original 2D & 3D artwork in a myriad of styles. Proficient in the development of team or solo based projects that require extensive planning & tight deadlines. Design capabilities range, but are not limited to previsualization, illustrative, graphic, & sculptural.

# **EXPERIENCE**

LOS ANGELES **OPEN RANGE ARTMAKERS** MAY 2020 — PRESENT

# Lead Graphic Artist

- Design and create custom graphic artwork for health care settings.
- 0 Some clients include Kaiser Permanente, Montefiore, and Hospital for Special Surgery.
- Creating artwork with a purpose for members/patients that places an equal importance on mental and physical health.
- Leading creative team to build artwork with the location and space in mind through innovative printing techniques.
- Responsible for every single custom graphic created from conceptualization to production.

#### **KEVIN BARRY ART ADVISORY**

LAS VEGAS, NV

**APRIL 2018 - MARCH 2020** 

# Graphic Artist | 3D Artist

- Designed a high volume of artwork for various projects ranging from Hotels, Resorts, Public Spaces, & Private Residentials.
- Created visual aids that included shop drawings, elevations, and onsite photos with inserted artwork shown at 1:1 scale.
- Modeled sculpture designs with materials in 3D design software, submitted as high resolution renders.
- Critical thinking done during 3D prototyping phase to efficiently solve potential production dilemmas.

#### MAX ART PRODUCTIONS

#### LAS VEGAS. NV

**DECEMBER 2013 – APRIL 2018** 

# Graphic Artist | Production Artist | Photographer

- Graphic design creation for flyers, vehicle wraps, promotional materials, and video presentations.
- Photographing original artwork, post proofing, digital clean up, and producing faithfully authentic reproductions.
- Worked with renowned clients such as Charles Fazzino, Jim Carrey, Richard Oliver, and National Geographic Fine Art.

# **SOFTWARE**

#### **AUTODESK**

Maya
Mudbox

#### **PIXELOGIC**

• ZBrush • Sculptris

#### **ADOBE**

- Photoshop Illustrator Premiere Pro
- Indesign Procreate After Effects

# MICROSOFT OFFICE

• Word • PowerPoint • Outlook

# PRE-PRODUCTION

- 3D Modeling
- o 3D Prototyping
- **Digital Fine Art Creation**
- Mixed Media Mural Designs
- Graphics, Logo, Banner Design
- **Vector Based Designs**
- Elevation Mock-ups
- **Large Scale Layouts**

#### POST-PRODUCTION

**SKILLS** 

- **3D Scene Renders**
- 3D Print File Preparation
- **Shop Drawing Designs**
- To Scale Visual Aid Prints
- **Print Quality Inspection**
- **Digital Art Proofing** 0
- **Embellishments**
- **Vector Cutpath Creation**

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### **SAHARA**

o Collaboration with KBAA & Jaja Woods

### THE STRAT

- Collaboration with KBAA & Blue Tree
- Collaboration with KBAA & Jaja Woods
- o Featured at Blvd. & Main Taphouse VIP Event

# **SHERATON - DALLAS**

Collaboration with KBAA & James J. Farran

"LOVE" Scrabbleboard Sculpture 2020

"Ebb & Flow" Main Lobby Sculpture 2019 **View Lounge Neon Sculpture 2019 Mixed Media Mural 2019** 

**Large Scale Lenticular Sculpture 2018** 

# **EDUCATION**